PROFESSOR: All right, let's see what
breadth-first search does.
Breadth-first search essentially takes
the same mountain and rather than
drilling down, which has this problem
that you could go very, very deep into
the graph and just not get anything,
breadth-first search goes in layers.
CS1 does not endorse strip mining but
that's basically what breadth-first
search does.
Top layer, second layer,
third layer, and so on.
Let's see breadth-first
search as a strategy.
It's still a tree search.
It's that same general algorithm but
as a strategy it always expands a
shallowest note first.
At the beginning, what's on my fringe?
Just S, so it's the shallowest
note so I take it off.
Now what's on my fringe?
D, E, and P, and again, they're all
equally shallow just like they were
equally deep.
Here's where it gets different
from breadth-first search.
What are we going to pop off first?
We might expand D first, just like
before, but now we've got nodes at two
different levels.
We've got the B,C, and E nodes at depth
two, and the E and P nodes at
depth one, and we're going to continue
with the shallow ones.
So now we kind of go
to E and then to P.
So the way this has worked we did the
first layer, S, and then we did D, E
and P on the second layer.
And only once that depth
two is exhausted, do I
move on to depth three.
OK So then I'll do B, C, and so on,
and you can see that the way this
search will precede is in tiers.
It will do all the depth one things,
then all the depth two things, and all
the depth three things, and so
on until you hit a goal.